Inventory of the Ernest Emery Harmon Papers, 1909-1949
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Ernest Emery Harmon papers
1909-1949
Harmon, Ernest Emery
03160
.45 cubic ft. + oversize (2 containers)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Photographs and papers of an Air Force aviator who piloted the first flight around the rim of the continental United States in 1919.
Biography of Ernest Emery Harmon
Ernest Emery Harmon (1893-1933) was an aviator in the Air Corps of the United States. He joined the Air Corps in 1917. In 1919 he piloted the first flight around the rim of the continental United States, a trip that took three months to complete. In 1932 Harmon was commissioned a captain. He was killed jumping from an airplane in 1933. Ernest Harmon Air Force Base in Newfoundland was named for him in 1949.
Scope and Content
The collection contains biographical information about Harmon and his family; photographs of Harmon, his family, and colleagues; newspaper clippings about the 1919 around-the-rim flight; and speeches from the dedication of Harmon Air Force Base.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Ernest Emery Harmon at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Ernest E. Harmon Jr. (son) in 1969.
Access Terms
Ernest Harmon Air Force Base; United States. Army. Air Service; Aeronautics -- United States -- 20th century; Transcontinental flights -- United States
Transportation; Military; Science, Technology and Health; Technology
Container List
- Biographical/Miscellaneous (includes High School diploma), 1909-1936 (Box 1)
- Military Manual of Interior Guard Duty, U.S. Army, 1914 (Box 1)
- Newspaper Clippings - Around the Rim Flight, 1919 (Box 1)
- Patent Designs for Airplanes and Guns (not by Harmon), undated (Box 1)
- Photographs: Harmon, Ernest E. and Family, 1911-1933 (Box 1)
- Photographs: Harmon, Ernest E. - Military, circa 1917-1933 (Box 1-2)
- Photographs: Harmon, Ernest E. - Sports, circa 1910-1917 (Box 1)
- Photographs: Harmon, Ernest E. with Airplanes and Colleagues, circa 1917-1920s (Box 1)
- Photographs: Panama/France Field, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
- Photographs: Selaisse, Haile, - Examining Aircraft, undated (Box 1)
- Photographs: Washington D.C. - Aerial Views, circa 1920s (Box 1)
- Speeches - Harmon Air Force Base Dedication, 1949 (Box 1)
- Pilot's Book of E.E. Harmon, 1918 (Box 1)
- Yearbook, "Bethanian" - Bethany College (photograph of E.E. Harmon as Junior student has been cut out), 1912 (Box 1)
- Yearbook, "The Echo" - Tyler County High School (with photograph of E.E. Harmon as Faculty), 1917 (Box 1)